

Javier YONG Xue Liang

(+65) 83682097 javier.yongxl@gmail.com | 30 years old | SINGAPORE

Experience 7 years

Education RMIT University

B.Bus (Accountancy) (2012)

Nationality Singaporean

Experience

Nov 2014 – Present (2.7 years)

Finance Executive, Fund Finance (China and India Markets)

CapitaLand Fund Management Pte Ltd. | Singapore

- Review of consolidated fund financials for 3 private equity funds (2 China funds and 1 India fund) with a portfolio of 21 shopping malls (~AUM S\$ 4billion)
- Reporting directly to various parties including fund managers, finance manager and Assistant Vice
 President (Finance) and Head of Finance (CapitaMalls Asia)
- Recommend and advise China and India finance counterparts (Manager levels and above) on consolidation entries and not limiting to the proper accounting of financial derivatives, hedge accounting, withholding tax etc, in accordance with IFRS.
- Provide quarterly investor reporting and financial analysis to fund managers and top management.
- · Written fund papers for board of directors and investment committee's approval on fund related matters
- Liaise with Group Treasury on fund related financing and hedging matters
- Prepare, lead and oversees entire de-registration of fund's onshore Hong Kong and China subsidiaries including providing forecasts of potential group financial impact upon de-registration
- Liase with auditors, prepare and draft financial statements for respective fund on behalf of trustees
- Worked, presented and advised management on side projects such as potential acquisitions in India
- Conduct monthly meetings with overseas finance counterparts to further understand on variances such as actual against budget and month-on-month.
- Plan for entire fund finance team on submission deadlines and final reviewer of all fund numbers before
 release of financials.
- Appointed Independent Compliance Officer for CapitaMalls Asia Malaysia REIT.
- Work closely with fund managers, provide financial data as required for financial modelling and analysis
- Part of the organizing committee for finance quarterly gatherings

Successfully managed to convince Head of Finance and top management to reject a potential tender of an India shopping mall under the government of India, based on analysis from financial standpoint of terms stated in the Tender Agreement as overall impact to the group is very unfavorable.

Lead and oversee in the de-registration exercise of fund related subsidiaries.

Apr 2013 – Oct 2014 (1.8 years)

Audit Associate II

Reanda Adept Public Accounting Corporation | Singapore

Having graduated with a degree and with some finance exposure, I decided to step up as a reviewer instead, and was offered a position as an audit associate II with a Top 20 public accounting firm. This is a fast tracked position considering entry level graduates are mostly offered associate I.

Portfolio

28 engagements (including local and overseas)

Managed a team of 6 associates,
 Report and Accountable to Senior Associates, Audit Manager and Audit Partner directly

Managing 28 different engagements including external audit and compilation for clients, my role was to ensure engagements assigned are completed on time and provide necessary guidance to junior associates with reference to the following:

- Develop audit plans and deadlines with Senior Associates and Managers
- Understand audit objectives to be achieved and client's business, study on financial reporting standards applicable to their business nature and in-house preparation work
- Develop and manage training for junior associates and briefing on upcoming engagements
- Perform external audit and compilation engagements for clients within South East Asia (local and overseas) in accordance to IFRS and SSA requirements
- Met up with clients' Top Management to discuss on potential audit issues and in depth understanding of business
- Translate and comply overseas financial statements (China) in accordance to IFRS for performing of further audit works
- Provide weekly updates to senior associate and managers on engagement status
- Reviewing of work papers from junior associates, provide guidance if necessary Analyze reasonableness of client's financials and justify audit work to managers
- Successfully conducted due diligence for clients (Avalon club and Ku De Ta: Marina Bay Sands)
- Worked and successfully provide litigation evidence for an overseas client facing legal case.
- Drive & manage team towards deadlines, ensure no compromise towards work quality.

Successfully conducted overseas consolidated group audit in Malaysia and China

Due diligence review on behalf of clients (Avalon Club and Ku De Ta) which led to their eventual acquisitions.

Defended our client in legal case successfully with evidence from our litigation support work in Thailand.

Nov 2010 - Mar 2013 (2.5 years)

Accounts Executive European and Middle East region

TSA Training Services Pte Ltd | Singapore

Portfolio:

Accounting (Full Set) for European and Middle East Regions (~70+ countries)

(Converted to full time finance staff in Nov 2010, subsequently promoted to Accounts Executive)

Knowing that I was pursuing an Accountancy degree, the CFO offered me a full time finance role as an accounts assistant even though I had no relevant qualifications at that time. I reported directly to the Senior Accountant and CFO and was tasked as personal assistant (PA) to CEO.

- Responsible for accurate and timely book keeping of European and Middle East Regions accounts
- Helped further improve SOPs for debt recovery and credit control
- Analyze and provide management with financial data, yearly and quarterly results
- Successfully migrated to new accounting system and provide valuable suggestions and feedback on systems during UAT
- Worked closely with overseas credit controller on following up of SOAs and debtors aging
- Part of the committee for corporate events to boost cohesiveness
- Personal assistant to CEO of the company handling his bank accounts and cheques, tabulate and provide financial reports on his income and expenses (cash-accounting), booking of accommodation and flights for personal holidays/training seminars, track his personal stock portfolio.
- · Liaised with auditors on issues.

Jul 2009 – Oct 2010 (1 year)

IT Support Assistant, (Temp) Asean, European and Middle East region

TSA Training Services Pte Ltd | Singapore

Portfolio:

Generate statistic reports for established hotel chains within Asean, European and Middle East Regions (~130+ countries including Singapore)

While waiting for university studies to commence and armed with an IT diploma, I applied for this position and was contracted with part time assignments. I reported directly to the Director of IT, handled regional customer support as well as formulate and improve on the current IT system.

- Report directly to Director of Information Technology of the business handling statistic reports generation for all hotel management and provide regional support.
- Analyze data files sent by clients for any irregularities and discrepancies, re-configure data files and generate statistic reports for hotel management.
- Successfully setup network infrastructure and configurations for clients with trainers based onsite (Ritz Carlton, Jumeirah Hotel and Resorts, Six Senses Hotel and Resorts, Marriott International and IHG, Hilton Hotels, Amari Hotels and Centara Hotels and Resorts)
- Work closely with Information Systems team in resolving client issues and provide constructive feedback on system improvement

Jan 2009- Jun 2009 (6 months)

Waiter (Temp)

Marina Mandarin Hotel

2007-2008

Sales Officer (Temp)

(2 years)

Fujitsu Asia Pacific

2004-2006 (3 years) **Ride Operator (Temp)**

Sentosa (3D Ride)

Education

Current ISCA (Professional Examination)

ISCA Associate Member for Chartered Accountant | Singapore

2012 RMIT University

Bachelor of Business (Accountancy) | Singapore

2006 Ngee Ann Polytechnic

Diploma in IT (Mobile Computing) | Singapore

Financial Skillsets

Advanced External Audit and Compilation, Litigation Support, Financial Consolidation and Analysis, Budgeting

& Forecasting (including cashflow and loan forecast), IRS & FX Hedging, Financial Derivatives, Consolidated Cashflows, Financial Statements drafting, Accounts Receivable, Accounts Payable and

General Ledger functions

Business Travel Exposure

Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur), Thailand (Bangkok and Pattaya), China (Beijing, Nanjing and Shanghai)

Languages

Proficiency level: 0 - Poor, 10 - Excellent

Language Spoken Written Relevant Certificates

English (Primary) 9 9 O Levels Chinese Mandarin 9 7 O Levels

Additional Info

Expected Salary SGD 4,900 (negotiable)
Preferred Work Location Anywhere in Singapore

Other Information

Skill Name Skill Level Years of Experience

SAP Intermediate 3 years IBM Cognos Controller Intermediate 3 years Intermediate 3 years Sun Systems Quickbooks by Quicken Intermediate 3 years 12 years MS PowerPoint Advanced MS Excel Advanced 12 years MS Word Advanced 12 years 7 years Public Speaking Advanced

LANGUAGE SKILLS:

Good command of English and Chinese Language.

Spoken and Written: English, Mandarin and Cantonese

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS:

-Financial Consolidation (IFRS approach)

awarded by Institute of Chartered Accountants (ISCA) (2013 and 2016)

-Excel Budgeting Techniques

awarded by Institute of Chartered Accountants (ISCA) (2016)

-FRS Technical Updates

awarded by KPMG Singapore (2014 and 2015)

-Professional Certificate in Conversational Business Mandarin

awarded by Nanyang Technological University (NTU) (2008)

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

2010 to 2012:

RMIT University (collaboration with Singapore Institute of Management Global Education) Bachelor of Business (Accountancy) eligible for exemptions under CPA Australia

2007 to 2009:

Singapore Armed Forces

Enlisted in SAF and graduated as an Armour Infantry Section Commander, the only cadet posted to an active unit among all trainees. As point section commander for majority of the missions critical, was tasked as the point navigator for the entire brigade (~600 men). Lead and conducted training for my platoon and company which went on to win Best Combat Unit and Best Company (Army Training Evaluation).

2004 to 2006

Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Singapore

Diploma in Information Technology (Mobile Computing), with e-commerce website as final year project.

Part of the outward bound adventures team and cycled 120km to Malaysia Desaru for 3D2N camp

2000 to 2003

Chestnut Drive Secondary School, Singapore

Passed G.C.E. 'O' level and obtained full certificate with 6 O level passes

About Me

My exposures in working closely with Top Management, overseas assignments coupled with audit, accounting and consolidation experience have given me the confidence in holding this position. Clear-minded Problem Solver and executor, keen interest in different cultures, strong sense of responsibility, good interpersonal skills are qualities developed from my professional and other experiences.

During my leisure time, I love watching war and history documentaries, analyze stocks, and cycle. Occasionally I will volunteer as a helper in SPCA as I have a liking for pets.